Okay, so now from this video onwards, we will start adding missions or you can say objectives
to work in which we will tell the player or you can say handy player to go find a gun
and when the player is going to find a gun, we will then add a few zombies there or
you can say spawn zombies there so that there are difficulty in order to complete each
objective all right or you can say we want to make a storyline all right so this
can go hardcore into your own liking if you want whatever story for your game but
if you want to make the sex story as mine then you can follow me stem by step
right the first thing which we're going to do is in the zombies folder let's
create a new folder now by the name of prefabs right because right now we
will be making a prefab of each of their zombie and we will be spawning them
all right they will not be available in the environment like this because if
there are ten of zombies already in the environment the game will become
really laggy all right so that's why I make prefab of all of these zombies
because everything is set up and then deleted all right now we have this
prefabs right there these are the main FBX files all right then after this
let's go ahead and create a folder by the name of scripts all right now in
the scripts we will be making some scripts but first of all in order to show
the UI for the missions or objective we need to make some UI all right we have
this UI right here so if you open the player related user interface then
user and here as you can see we have this message panel and then these are the
own screen warnings okay so just disable the message panel or you can
actually leave it as enabled if you want okay but we don't have any message so
that's why I've told you to disable them okay so I'm just gonna disable it
then what I'm gonna do is in UI I'm gonna create a canvas let's name this as
objectives canvas all right in this objective canvas we will go ahead and
create a UI panel okay there is the panel right there let's make it black and
then make sure to select this right transform hold down the control button in order
to move it to the middle and these options are also now valuable let's make the
width sound 100 and the height to be 90 and then let's move to the top center right there
all right and what we're gonna do is we're gonna move it over down now let's
decrease the height to 60 and the width should be let's just say 400 or white no we
can name this as objective UI and then inside the objective UI let's go ahead
and add a legacy text all right the text color should be white and text should be
bold let's stretch it on all sides then move it to the middle like that and if
you want to see the UI change to to remove directly on this objective canvas
and here it is all right now what we can do is let's just say find something
or protection zombies where this will be the first hand or you can say the
first objective for the player this is just a dummy text you can type whatever
you want let's make it 20 so that we are able to see it and of course there can
be different types of sizes for different types of pieces okay I mean
the screen sizes so in order to make this UI work on all of them you will
have to change this from constant pixel size to scale with skin size and when
you do that as you can see it has now become really bigger so you can decrease
it size but I think I like this one so I'm just gonna do a bit of changes I think
the I but I think I'm just gonna leave this as it is okay and disable this
so objective UI and leave the objective canvas as it is just make sure to
change this from text to objective name all right now once we do that in the
next video now we're gonna add some coding in which we will show the objective
and when the objective is completed we will move to the next one all right
and when all of the objectives have completed we just gonna say that all
objective completed and then the mission will be passed or you can see the
mission will be successful something like that case so this turns you guys in
the next one